cssd.ab.ca 2019-05-21

# CCSD

  1. Home
  2. Internet Portal
  3. Privacy

#### Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP)

The Calgary Catholic School District (CCSD) website connects you to CCSD schools and departments. This website is maintained to assist you in finding information about the CCSD, its schools, programs and services. The Calgary Catholic School District is subject to the Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act, and is committed to providing a website that respects your privacy while you visit us online. This privacy statement summarizes the privacy practices of the Calgary Catholic School District with respect to our website located at www.cssd.ab.ca. 

We do not automatically gather any personal information from you, such as your name, phone number, or email address. This information is obtained only if you supply it voluntarily, usually through contacting us via email or by providing it on an online form. You should review the privacy statement each time you submit personal information on the website. 

Any personal information you do provide is managed according to the FOIP Act. This means that at the point of collection, you will be informed of the purpose for which your personal information is being collected, the legal authority for collection and the person who can answer your questions about the collection. The Calgary Catholic School District does not sell or otherwise distribute any information collected to third parties. 

#### Information collected in Emails & online forms

We treat emails with the same respect we treat letters sent to the Calgary Catholic School District. We do not collect personal information for any purpose other than to respond to you. The only personal information collected that is used to identify you is information you give voluntarily. When you submit a question or comment, you may be asked for your name, email address, or other information. This personal information is used to process and respond to your question or comment and is only disclosed to those who need it to answer your question, to the person that your inquiry relates to or to parties legislatively authorized to receive the information. 

If you complete an online form and submit it to us through our website, we use that information for the purposes described on the form. Personal information collected from an online form will be treated in accordance with the privacy protection provisions of the FOIP Act. 

#### Information collected & stored automatically

When you visit the Calgary Catholic School District website, our web server automatically collects a limited amount of standard information essential to the operation, security and evaluation of the website. This information includes: 

  * IP address from which you access the CCSD website (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web), type and version of browser used to access our site, date and time you access our site, pages you visit, and if you linked to the CCSD website from another website, the address of that site. 

This information is collected in compliance with the FOIP Act. The information is primarily used to help us to assess our services in order to efficiently provide you with the information you require. 

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of text information that is sent to your browser when you access a website. Your browser will return this cookie information to the domain where the cookie originated. Cookies may be created when you visit our site. The session cookie we incorporate allows us to determine common paths used by our viewers. This information allows us to streamline navigation to the most requested pages during future upgrades. 

If you are concerned about the use of cookies, you can refer to the help information in your browser software for information on how to disable cookies. If you wish to delete cookies from your machine, consult your browser’s help files for instructions on how to do so. 

#### Security

For site security purposes and to ensure that web services remain available to all users, the district’s computer system uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage to the service we provide. No attempt is made to identify an individual user or their usage patterns except for law enforcement investigations. 

#### Links to other websites

This website contains links to other sites. The Calgary Catholic School District is not responsible for the content or the privacy practices of other websites. You are encouraged to examine each site’s privacy policy and disclaimers and make your own decisions regarding the accuracy, reliability and correctness of material and information found. 

#### Questions about the FOIP Act?  

Questions about the FOIP Act as it relates to the Calgary Catholic School District and concerns regarding privacy or access to information issues should be directed to: 

FOIP Coordinator  
Calgary Catholic School District, Central Office  
1000 – 5 Avenue SW  
Calgary, Alberta T2P 4T9  
Phone: 403-500-2000  
Fax: 403-500-2914 

#### Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP)

The Calgary Catholic School District (CCSD) website connects you to CCSD schools and departments. This website is maintained to assist you in finding information about the CCSD, its schools, programs and services. The Calgary Catholic School District is subject to the Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act, and is committed to providing a website that respects your privacy while you visit us online. This privacy statement summarizes the privacy practices of the Calgary Catholic School District with respect to our website located at www.cssd.ab.ca. 

We do not automatically gather any personal information from you, such as your name, phone number, or email address. This information is obtained only if you supply it voluntarily, usually through contacting us via email or by providing it on an online form. You should review the privacy statement each time you submit personal information on the website. 

Any personal information you do provide is managed according to the FOIP Act. This means that at the point of collection, you will be informed of the purpose for which your personal information is being collected, the legal authority for collection and the person who can answer your questions about the collection. The Calgary Catholic School District does not sell or otherwise distribute any information collected to third parties. 

#### Information collected in Emails & online forms

We treat emails with the same respect we treat letters sent to the Calgary Catholic School District. We do not collect personal information for any purpose other than to respond to you. The only personal information collected that is used to identify you is information you give voluntarily. When you submit a question or comment, you may be asked for your name, email address, or other information. This personal information is used to process and respond to your question or comment and is only disclosed to those who need it to answer your question, to the person that your inquiry relates to or to parties legislatively authorized to receive the information. 

If you complete an online form and submit it to us through our website, we use that information for the purposes described on the form. Personal information collected from an online form will be treated in accordance with the privacy protection provisions of the FOIP Act. 

#### Information collected & stored automatically

When you visit the Calgary Catholic School District website, our web server automatically collects a limited amount of standard information essential to the operation, security and evaluation of the website. This information includes: 

  * IP address from which you access the CCSD website (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web), type and version of browser used to access our site, date and time you access our site, pages you visit, and if you linked to the CCSD website from another website, the address of that site. 

This information is collected in compliance with the FOIP Act. The information is primarily used to help us to assess our services in order to efficiently provide you with the information you require. 

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of text information that is sent to your browser when you access a website. Your browser will return this cookie information to the domain where the cookie originated. Cookies may be created when you visit our site. The session cookie we incorporate allows us to determine common paths used by our viewers. This information allows us to streamline navigation to the most requested pages during future upgrades. 

If you are concerned about the use of cookies, you can refer to the help information in your browser software for information on how to disable cookies. If you wish to delete cookies from your machine, consult your browser’s help files for instructions on how to do so. 

#### Security

For site security purposes and to ensure that web services remain available to all users, the district’s computer system uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage to the service we provide. No attempt is made to identify an individual user or their usage patterns except for law enforcement investigations. 

#### Links to other websites

This website contains links to other sites. The Calgary Catholic School District is not responsible for the content or the privacy practices of other websites. You are encouraged to examine each site’s privacy policy and disclaimers and make your own decisions regarding the accuracy, reliability and correctness of material and information found. 

#### Questions about the FOIP Act?  

Questions about the FOIP Act as it relates to the Calgary Catholic School District and concerns regarding privacy or access to information issues should be directed to: 

FOIP Coordinator  
Calgary Catholic School District, Central Office  
1000 – 5 Avenue SW  
Calgary, Alberta T2P 4T9  
Phone: 403-500-2000  
Fax: 403-500-2914
